asabe.org 2019-04-24

# 

ASABE Privacy Policy
ASABE respects your privacy. We take seriously the privacy of members and customers, and our
commitment to protecting your personal information.
Scope
This privacy policy applies to all personal data processed by employers and volunteers when
acting on behalf of ASABE, contractors and partners doing business on behalf of ASABE, as well
as all legal entities, all operating locations in all countries, and all business processes conducted
by ASABE.
What information do we collect?
ASABE collects the following personal data in line with the use purposes explained in this
document:
    •    Your name and contact details
    •    Date of birth
    •    Online profile data/usage
    •    Emergency contact information
    •    Social media profile information
    •    Copies of identification documents
    •    Education and professional information
    •    Purchasing and payment information
    •    Charitable donations to ASABE and the ASABE Foundation
    •    Technical expertise
    •    Committee activity
    •    Registration and participation in ASABE events and activities
    •    Subscription preferences
    •    Information about the device(s) you use
    •    Information about service usage
    •    Cookies
    •    Authentication data
    •    Location information
    •    Author and peer review information
    •    Other information you upload or provide to us
                                                                                                     1

How do we use your information?
ASABE never sells your personal information. We occasionally share information with third
parties with whom we contract to provide products and services, such as electronic newsletters
and event administration.
ASABE uses (and, where specified, shares) your personal information for the following
purposes.
To process transactions
ASABE uses personal information to engage in interactions with you, including contacting you
about your order, donation, subscription, event participation, or membership. We use
financial/credit card and payment information to process your order and may need to share
some of this information with delivery services, credit card clearing houses, and other third
parties to complete the transaction.
To provide support or other services
ASABE may use your personal information to provide you with support or other services that
you have ordered or requested. ASABE may also use your personal information to respond
directly to your requests for information, including registrations for newsletters, webinars, or
other specific requests, or pass your contact information to the appropriate ASABE partner for
further follow-up related to your interests.
To provide information based on your needs and respond to your requests
ASABE may use your personal information to provide you with notices of new product releases
and service developments.
To provide online forums and social networks
Some services available on the websites permit you to participate in interactive discussions,
post comments, opportunities, or other content to a bulletin board or exchange, or otherwise
engage in networking activities. Some of these services are moderated; all may be accessed for
technical reasons (for example, for improvements or fixes). ASABE does not control the content
that users post to these forums or ASABE-related social networks. ASABE encourages you to be
prudent in providing personal information on all ASABE and other public forums and to review
any additional terms and conditions that may govern your use of such forms, including terms
related to sharing your personal information and receiving communications.
To administer products
ASABE may contact you if you purchase products to confirm certain information about your
order (for example, that you did not experience problems in the download process). We may
                                                                                                 2

also use this information to confirm compliance with licensing and other terms of use and may
share it with your company/institution.
To select content, improve quality, and facilitate use of ASABE’s website
We may use your personal information, including the information gathered as a result of site
navigation and electronic protocols and cookies (including third-party cookies), to help create
and personalize website content, improve website quality, evaluate page-response rates,
conduct usability testing, and facilitate your use of the websites (for example, to facilitate
navigation and the login process, avoid duplicate data entry, enhance security, keep track of
shopping cart additions, and preserve order information between sessions).
To assess usage of ASABE products and services
ASABE may track your usage of ASABE products and services (e.g., ASABE Forums) to determine
your level of usage, and those statistics may be made available to partners with whom ASABE
may contract for the purposes of improving our services to you.
To communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event
 We may communicate with you about a meeting, conference, or event hosted or co-sponsored
by ASABE or one of our business associates. This may include information about the event's
program, venue, travel and accommodations, payment, updates, and additional information
related to the event. Information you provide when registering for or participating in a
conference managed or co-sponsored by parties, other than or in addition to ASABE may be
shared with those parties, and the treatment of such information is further subject to the
privacy policies of those parties. ASABE and its conference co-sponsors may contact you after
the event about the event, subsequent iterations of the event and related events.
To consider you for professional recognition. ASABE may use personal information such as your
name, education, work history, and volunteer activities to consider you for an award or
nomination to Fellow status. ASABE may need to share this information with your nominators,
references, judges, and others parties involved in evaluating your eligibility.
To include you in the ASABE Member Roster
The ASABE network is a valuable benefit of membership. Your contact information is made
available to other ASABE members by way of the ASABE Member Roster, published in print and
electronic format. To advance our members as authoritative sources of information related to
the scope of the agricultural and biological engineering profession, we may provide contact
information in response to inquiries from media, educators, and others seeking one-on-one
communication with subject-matter experts.
                                                                                                3

To document standards development participation
If you are a participant in ASABE standards development, ASABE uses your personal information
to comply with policies and procedures, legal and accreditation requirements, and evaluation of
patent claims by patent offices. ASABE must capture your personal data for these purposes;
doing so provides information about activities related to standards development groups in
which you participate. ASABE standards development participation is documented through
various methods, e.g., rosters, submission documents, email reflectors, records of meeting
attendance, responses to ballots, publicly available participation lists, and declaration of
affiliations.
To assist in your participation in ASABE activities
ASABE will communicate with you if you are participating in certain ASABE activities such as
ASABE conferences, authoring or reviewing ASABE journals, or ASABE technical committees.
ASABE may send you information such as newsletters related to those activities.
To update you on relevant ASABE benefits, programs, and opportunities
ASABE may communicate with you regarding relevant ASABE benefits, programs, and
opportunities available to you, through your membership with ASABE.
To engage with third parties
ASABE may share your personal data with third parties in connection with services that these
individuals or entities perform for or with ASABE. These third parties are restricted from using
this data in any way other than to provide services for ASABE or for the collaboration in which
they and ASABE are contractually engaged (for example, hosting an ASABE database or
engaging in data processing on ASABE’s behalf, or mailing you information that you requested).
These third parties are carefully selected by ASABE and obligated to keep your data secure.
From time to time, we may also share your information with third parties whom we think might
provide content, products, or services of interest to you.
To protect ASABE content and services
We may use your information to prevent potentially illegal activities and to enforce our terms
and conditions. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address
anomalous activity and to screen content to prevent abuse, such as spam. These efforts may,
on occasion, result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions
for some users.
To get feedback or input from you
In order to deliver products and services of most interest to our customers, from time to time,
we may ask members, customers, volunteers, and website visitors to provide us input and
feedback (for example through surveys, usability studies, focus groups).
                                                                                                 4

To protect ASABE information assets as well as your own personal data
The ASABE Information Security Program protects the confidentiality, integrity, and availability
of ASABE information assets by following a risk management approach based on policies,
standards, guidelines, and procedures to meet security objectives while supporting business
and operational goals.
How can you control your information?
You can control the information we have about you and how we use it:
    •   If you are a registered user, you can log in to www.asabe.org to review, revise, and
        correct the personal data that you have provided to ASABE, or contact Membership
        Services at 269/429-0300 to request such changes.
    •   Use the Unsubscribe request provided in our various communications.
Personal data about minors and children
ASABE does not knowingly collect data from or about children under 16 without the permission
of parent(s)/guardian(s). If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child
under 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might
have any information from or about a child under age 16, please contact us.
How will you know if the Privacy Policy is changed?
ASABE may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes we will
notify you by email, or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming
effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our
privacy practices.
Technical and regulatory information
Logging practices
ASABE automatically records the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of visitors. The IP address is a
unique number assigned to every computer on the internet. Generally, an IP address changes
each time you connect to the internet (it is a "dynamic" address). Note, however, that if you
                                                                                                  5

have a broadband connection, depending on your individual circumstance, the IP address that
we collect may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because, with
some broadband connections, your IP address doesn't change (it is "static") and could be
associated with your personal computer.
As well as recording the IP addresses of users, ASABE may also keep track of sites that users
visited immediately prior to visiting ASABE’s website and the search terms they used to find it.
We keep track of the pages visited on ASABE’s website, the amount of time spent on those
pages and the types of searches done on them. Your searches remain confidential and
anonymous. ASABE uses this information only for statistical purposes to find out which pages
users find most useful and to improve the website.
ASABE also captures and stores information that you transmit. This may include:
     •  Browser/Device type/version
     •  Operating system used
     •  Media Access Control (MAC) address
     •  Date and time of the server request
     •  Volume of data transferred
External links behavior
ASABE’s website links to other sites created and maintained by other public- and/or private-
sector organizations. ASABE provides these links solely for your information and convenience.
When you transfer to an outside website, you are leaving the ASABE domain, and ASABE’s
information management policies no longer apply. ASABE encourages you to read the privacy
statement of each external website that you visit before you provide any personal data.
Cookies and web beacons
Cookies and web beacons are electronic placeholders that are placed on your device by
websites to track your individual movements on that website over time. ASABE uses both
session-based cookies (which last only for the duration of the user's session) and persistent
cookies (which remain on your device and provides information about the session you are in
and waits for the next time you use that site again).
These cookies and web beacons provide useful information to ASABE, enabling us to recognize
repeat users, facilitate the user's access to and use of our sites, allows us to track usage
behavior, and to balance the usage of our websites on all ASABE web servers.
Tracking cookies, third-party cookies, and other technologies such as web beacons may be used
to process additional information, enable non-core functionalities on the ASABE website and
                                                                                                 6

enable third-party functions (such as a social media "share" link). We may also include web
beacons and other similar technology in promotional email messages to determine whether the
messages have been opened.
Do Not Track (DNT)
The online advertising industry has self-regulatory initiatives designed to provide consumers a
choice in the types of ads they may see online and to conveniently opt-out from online
behavioral ads served by some or all of the companies participating in these programs. Our
websites do not respond to DNT consumer browser settings.
Transfer of information to other countries
As a global organization, ASABE engages in a number of international activities. In connection
with the management of those activities, ASABE may transfer information to other countries.
By submitting your information to ASABE via the websites, or in connection with your
interactions with ASABE offline, you consent to such transfers and to the processing of this
information in other countries.
Responses to legal requests
ASABE reserves the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information
requests of governmental authorities or where required by law.
In the event of bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your
information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this privacy
policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.
Your European Union privacy rights
Under the General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation EU 2016/679) (also known as GDPR),
if you are an individual protected by the GDPR you may have certain rights as a data subject. To
request information about or avail yourself of those rights, please send an email to
privacy@ASABE.org with "GDPR Request" in the subject line. In the email please describe, with
specificity, the GDPR right you are requesting assistance with. Please note additional
information may be requested prior to initiation of a request and that ASABE reserves the right
to charge a fee with respect to certain requests. Upon ASABE’s completion of its review you will
be notified if your request has been granted, denied, or exemptions apply.
Your California privacy rights
Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (also known as S.B. 27), if you are a California
resident and your business relationship with ASABE is primarily for personal, family, or
household purposes, you may request certain data regarding ASABE’s disclosure, if any, of
personal information to third parties for the third-parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make
such a request, please send an email to privacy@ASABE.org with "Request for California Privacy
                                                                                                 7

Information" in the subject line. You may make such a request up to once per calendar year. If
applicable, we will provide you, by email, a list of the categories of personal information
disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding
calendar year, along with the third parties' names and addresses. Please note that not all
personal information sharing is covered by S.B. 27's requirements.
Contact
privacy@ASABE.org
American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers
2950 Niles Rd
St Joseph MI 49085-9659
USA
269/429-0300
Published: May 23, 2018
                                                                                                8
